

wstevenbg@gmail.com



Medellín, Colombia

LINKS

Linkedin:

htps:/www.linkedin.com/in/wilhelmboada/

SKILLS

Scala, Java, SBT, Akka HTTP, Circe, Cats, Flyway, TestContainer, Junit, ScalaTest, SQL and NoSQL Databases, Git, Git flow, New Relic, AWS, GCP, Vavr, Apache Beam Framework, Spring Boot, Dataflow, Jenkins, LInux, macOS

LANGUAGES

Spanish

English

Wilhelm Steven Boada Guerrero

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ABOUTME

Professional with more than six years of experience working as a backend software developer, with international experience on distributed teams, building reactive microservices with functional and object-oriented programming. I have expertise on layered architecture, CQRS to segregate responsibilities, and DDD approach to understand, design, and handle the client's business model. I have worked on different software life cycles. Also, proficient in both Spanish and English.

By working on different projects and different teams, I have been able to adapt quickly and easily to understand the core domain and the technologies used in each project. My idea is to apply the best practices I have learned to the way the team works. I am an enthusiast of learning, focused on brushing up my English skills in order to have beter communication with the team members, and to improve my knowledge in functional programming in languages like Scala and Java.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

S4N – EPAM / Medellín / Jan 2017 - Present

Nordstrom, Jan 2021 - Present (S4N - EPAM)

Built a product display service in charge of obtaining all the information of a product (prices, inventor, markets, etc.) from different external services to optimize the searches of Nordstrom employees.

- Performed integration with an external web service system on HTTP
- Exposed REST services to the frontend app
- Collaborated with the frontend team to fix bugs or create new features.
- Fixed bugs in a production environment, tracking logs with platforms like Splunk, k8s, and New Relic.
- Created metrics, widgets and alerts in New Relic.
- Developed functional and sustainable applications with clean code.
- Performed unit tests.
- Collaborated with the product team to define business rules and create new flows.
- Reviewed code to other team members.
- Helped to analyze and document infrastructure, architecture and integration with external services, etc used by the project.

Copa Airline, Jan 2020 - Present (S4N - EPAM)

Built a platform that allows Copa Airline to orchestrate business processes such as the creation of reservations and information about the trip of the passengers that enable a modern user experience with personalized products.

- Performed integration with an external web service system on HTTP
- Exposed REST services to the frontend app.
- Collaborated with the product team to define business rules and create new flows.

- Collaborated with the frontend team to fix bugs or create new features.
- Collaborated in the design of the client's business model.
- Built high-quality reusable code that can be used in the future.
- Developed functional and sustainable applications with clean codes.
- Performed unit tests.
- Checked code to other team members.

Protección, Jan 2019 - Dec 2019 (S4N - EPAM)

Built several backend services for a pension company to detect inconsistencies in a person's basic information, pension and work history.

- Performed integration with an external web service system on HTTP
- Exposed REST services to the frontend app.
- Collaborated with the product team to define business rules and create new flows.
- Collaborated in the design of the client's business model.
- Built high-quality reusable code that can be used in the future.
- Developed functional and sustainable applications with clean codes.
- · Performed unit tests.
- I checked code to other team members.

Suramericana, Jan 2017 - Dec 2018 (S4N - EPAM)

Collaborated and developed an application for the massive vehicle insurance policy for companies.

- Performed integration with an external web service system on HTTP
- Exposed REST services to the frontend app.
- Collaborated with the product team to define business rules and create new flows.
- Collaborated in the design of the client's business model.
- Built high-quality reusable code that can be used in the future.
- Developed functional and sustainable applications with clean codes.
- Performed unit tests.
- I checked code to other team members.

Software Developer

Informatix / Bucaramanga / Sep 2015 – Jan 2017

Created an application that allows managing all the processes of a company such as inventory, staff assignment, vehicle assignment, and monitoring of cocoa plantation and cultivation.

- Collaborated with frontend developers and different business and technology areas.
- Developed of requirements in Java.
- Performed unit tests with JUnit.

EDUCATION

Bachelor

Simón Bolívar University / Cúcuta / 2015

Systems Engineer